

SABA CHEEMA

Cell: +9306 4907707 170-A block Tariq Garden-Lahore

Email: sabacheema194@gmail.com

Linkedin profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saba-cheema-129456149/

OBJECTIVE

To obtain a position as a qualified employee with a well-established organization to utilize my educational background, skills and the ability to work well with people.

ABOUT ME

Hi, my name is Saba Cheema. I am 29 years old and currently residing in Lahore, Pakistan.

I have been working as an off-site content writer for the past 5-6 years and I have worked with innumerable websites. Ever since I have started working in this field, the passion of writing and working wholeheartedly grew in me even more. All of my clients have always appreciated me for my work and by the grace of Almighty all of my articles have always been in Google high ranking.

I have been involved in working as a Class Representative (CR) for almost 2 semesters throughout my Masters and MPhil degree in which I received great appreciation and applause for managing tasks and class activities in an organized manner.

I am a dependable person who is great at time management. I am flexible in my working hours, being able to work evenings and weekends. I have successfully met deadlines on every project I've worked on.

EDUCATION

Qualification	MPHIL in Educational Leadership and Management (CGPA: 3.75 GPA/ 4.0 scale)
Institution	University of Management and Technology
Session	2020-2022

Qualification	Masters in Educational Leadership and Management (CGPA: 3.5 GPA/ 4.0 scale)
Institution	University of Lahore
Session	2016 to 2018

Qualification	Bachelor in Arts (500/800) My subjects in BA were: Journalism Sociology Persian (optional)
Institution	Wapda Town Degree College, Lahore
Session	2014 to 2016

Qualification	F.A (2 nd division grade B)
Institution	Lahore College For Women University, Lahore
Session	2011 to 2013

Qualification	Matric with Science (Grade: A+)
Institution	Customs Public School System, Lahore
Session	2009 to 2011

EXPERIENCE

Administrative Officer | HR | Recruitment | Talent Acquisition | Pak-Turk Maarif International Schools and Colleges · Full-time Feb 2024 – Present

- Successfully managing student admissions process, ensuring smooth enrollment and registration for hundreds of students.
- Planning and leading the projects based on improving admissions
- Implementing a centralized database system for student records, resulting in improved data accuracy and accessibility.
- Implementing efficient scheduling and resource allocation systems, optimizing classroom utilization and minimizing conflicts.
- Collaborating with faculty and staff to develop and implement standardized administrative procedures, resulting in improved efficiency and consistency across the institution.
- Handling the attendance management system, reducing paperwork and streamlining the process for staff and faculty.
- Developing and conducting training programs on HR policies and procedures, ensuring compliance and fostering a positive work environment.
- Managing the recruitment and onboarding process for new staff and faculty members.
- Maintaining a record of all employees' testimonials, including CNIC, domicile, education/experience, certifications, and getting the employment affidavit signed by each employee.
- Handling employee relations issues, including conflict resolution and disciplinary actions.
- Coordinating employee benefits programs, such as health insurance

Working as Senior Academic Officer in the School of Architecture and Planning (SAP) University of Management and Technology - UMT · Full-time September 2023 – January 2024

- ❖ The representative of the department will be responsible for overseeing the entire admissions process and collaborating with the admissions office.
- ❖ Planning and executing orientation programs for each intake of incoming students.
- Collaborate with department chair and faculty to plan and execute seminars and workshops, and gather necessary materials.
- ❖ Work with the dean or head of department to develop yearly spending plans that meet all criteria.
- ❖ Coordinate with HR and accounts to process payments for teaching assistants and supervisors, as well as process their contracts.
- ❖ Dealing with and assisting students with a wide range of matters and solving their problems.
- Set up and keep accurate records of all communications, meetings, and reports.
- ❖ Work closely with the department head to build and sustain strong connections with other academic and staff members, making sure that any relevant information is shared promptly.
- ❖ Carry out the Chair of Department's other administrative assignments.

Working in LACAS School system, Valencia campus

Post: admission counselor/administrator

October 2022 - October 2023

- ♣ Communicating directly with parents and students, resolving their queries related to academics or any other social issue within school premises.
- **H**andle and monitor incoming communications and documents.
- ♣ Providing timely and accurate information in both internal and external by answering questions and requests.
- ♣ Maintaining a proper record of teacher's attendance and leave applications as well as custodial staff.
- ♣ Providing a general administrative and clerical support including mailing, and scanning.
- ♣ Keeping a record of entrance tests & results for new admission.
- ♣ Keeping a daily record of student's and staff's attendance.
- ♣ Handling resumes of staff & Induction of newly hired staff.
- ♣ Setting up Principal's appointments and schedule interviews.
- Creating and modifying documents using Microsoft Office.
- Maintain confidential record and files.

Web Content Writer

J&J rent a car

Full-time

August 2022-September 2023

Note: I am currently working for the website (J&J RENT A CAR) for which I produced the off-page and on-page content work.

Work as a Senior Content Writer

Rankistan Company

Full-time

Jan 2020 Till Sep 2022

Skills: Blogging, Article Writing, Article Editor

AWARDS

Honored with UMT Dean's Merit Award in 2022 for attaining highest CGPA of 3.9/4.0 in my session.

Participated in "2nd National Postgraduate Research e-Conference in Education 2021" for presenting a topic over "Analyzing Current Challenges in Educational and Policy Implementation in Pakistan"

Worked as a "class representative" for 2 years throughout my masters and MPhil degree

PERSONAL SKILLS

- ✓ Active listening skills
- ✓ Communication skills
- ✓ Work efficiently with others, projects or teams
- ✓ Management skills
- ✓ Complete tasks and projects before deadlines

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ❖ Microsoft Office (word, excel, spreadsheet, PowerPoint)
- ❖ Adobe Photoshop
- **❖** WordPress
- Windows movie maker

ACTIVITIES

- Article Writer in "Nation on Campus"
- Content Writer for Websites for Last 4 years
- Blog Writing Skills